<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Juan S. Mayorga on Juan S. Mayorga</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Juan S. Mayorga on Juan S. Mayorga</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>test</title>
      <link>/post/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/test/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapid and lasting gains from solving illegal fishing</title>
      <link>/publication/rapid_and_lasting_gains_from_solving_ilegal_fishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/rapid_and_lasting_gains_from_solving_ilegal_fishing/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking the Global Footprint of Fisheries</title>
      <link>/publication/tracking_the_global_footprint_of_fisheries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tracking_the_global_footprint_of_fisheries/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>/talk/example-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/example-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Embed your slides or video here using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;. Further details can easily be added using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Fishing Watch</title>
      <link>/project/global-fishing-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/global-fishing-watch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://globalfishingwatch.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Global Fishing Watch&lt;/a&gt; uses satellite technology, big data analytics, and machine learning, to illuminate the world&amp;rsquo;s fishing fleets with unprecedented resolution. By providing the public, governments, researchers, and management bodies with a near-real-time dataset of global fisheries, Global Fishing Watch is facilitating a revolution in fisheries management towards transparency, sustainability, and effective marine conservation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/gfw_effort.gif&#34; alt=&#34;GFW tracks&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Global Fishing Watch&amp;rsquo;s dynamic database represents the largest influx of new data into the fields of fisheries science and marine conservation. It is expanding the possibilities and the kind of research and management questions we can answer. Some of these questions we are working on are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does the global network of trans-boundary fisheries look like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who fishes the high seas, where, and how profitable is it? What is the role of government subsidies to enable high seas fisheries?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How well do we know where global catch is coming from?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What can we learn from the behavior of fishing fleets about the status of the underlying fish stocks?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do fishing fleets respond to the creation of protected areas?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the costs of creating large marine reserves in the high seas?
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pristine Seas</title>
      <link>/project/pristine-seas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/pristine-seas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nationalgeographic.org/projects/pristine-seas/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pristine Seas&lt;/a&gt; is a project created by National Geographic&amp;rsquo;s Explorer-in-residence Dr. Enric Sala, to explore, document, and help protect the last wild places of the Ocean. By combining science, storytelling, economics, and policy, Pristine Seas has successfully worked to protect 16 unique marine ecosystems all around the world, covering a total area of 5.1 million square kilometers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/pristine-seas-map.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pristine Seas&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An important component of our work is to provide governments, not only with the ecological arguments to protect a special place, but also with the economic challenges and opportunities of creating a marine reserve. Usually, fisheries represent the most important challenge to overcome because reserves may directly displace their activities and affect the economic returns in the short-run. Therefore, having a good understanding of the distribution and intensity of fishing activities within a region of conservation priority is critical to assess the costs and trade-offs of designating a no-take marine reserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, however, information of fishing grounds, effort, and catches is rarely available and it is heavily guarded by the fishing industry; making the decision making process nontransparent. Now, Global Fishing Watch is allowing us to bring transparent data to the negotiating table and to objectively assess the potential impacts of a marine reserve on the fishing industry. This has been critical to advance the implementation of marine reserves in many of our recent expeditions, including: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nationalgeographic.org/expeditions/clipperton-atoll/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Clipperton Atoll Marine Protected Area&lt;/a&gt; (France), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nationalgeographic.org/expeditions/niue/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Niue Marine Protected Area&lt;/a&gt;, Revillagigedo National Park (Mexico), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nationalgeographic.org/expeditions/juan-fernandez-archipelago/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Juan Fernández Marine Park&lt;/a&gt;(Chile), and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nationalgeographic.org/expeditions/cape-horn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cape Horn - Diego Ramirez Marine Park&lt;/a&gt;  (Chile).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Network of Transboundary Fisheries</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;r-markdown&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;R Markdown&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
