<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Juan S. Mayorga</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Juan S. Mayorga</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Global Fishing Watch Data from Google Big Query using R</title>
      <link>/post/getting-global-fishing-watch-from-google-bigquery-using-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-global-fishing-watch-from-google-bigquery-using-r/</guid>
      <description>What is BigQuery Global Fishing Watch’s data in BigQuery Establishing a connection 1. Summarize the number of vessels by flag state and gear type 2. Make a time series of fishing effort for China’s trawlers fleet The dplyr way Why would I ever write SQL? The SQL way  3. Make a map of fishing effort for a particular region of the ocean Closing remarks   This blog post explains a couple of workflows to connect to Big Query using R, and access Global Fishing Watch’s public data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Global Network of Transnational Fisheries</title>
      <link>/post/mapping-the-global-network-of-transnational-fisheries/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mapping-the-global-network-of-transnational-fisheries/</guid>
      <description>The dataset Making the dataset spatial Making Great Circles Work Visualizing directionality Final plotting   Global Fishing Watch has opened the doors to a new era of transparency and accountability in industrial fisheries. Our recent paper in Science: “Tracking the global footprint of fisheries” introduced this database to the scientific community and highlighted some of the potential research and management applications. One of these is to examine the global network of transnational fisheries (i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>